Guide to the William Hillman Shockley Photographs, 1896-1922 and undated, bulk 1897-1909 RL.01177
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William Hillman Shockley photographs
1896-1922 and undated, bulk 1897-1909
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Shockley, W. H., 1855-1925
RL.01177
9.0 Linear Feet 20 boxes; approximately 3224 items
Collection contains over 2200 black-and-white photographs taken by W.H. (William Hillman) Shockley during his world travels as a mining engineer between the years 1896 to 1909. Locations include China (including Manchuria); Korea; India; Japan; Australia; and Russia (including Siberia); London; Washington, D.C.; and San Francisco; as well as several other south Asian locations. Subjects featured include local citizens and officials, and soldiers; Europeans (including businessmen, miners, diplomats, tourists, missionaries); indigenous peoples and their communities; mining operations (iron ore, gold, petroleum, and coal); ancient walls and forts; religious structures and art; street scenes; remote hamlets and camps; fields, rivers, mountains, geological formations, and other landscapes; domestic animals; and caravans and other forms of transportation, including railroads. There are many other work scenes in addition to mining settings. Formats include more than 2000 small vintage prints, over 400 modern prints, and over 400 nitrate film and glass plate negatives. Many of the photographs bear original captions. There are also some Shockley family photographs, correspondence (1905-1922), a notebook from India, and a few items of memorabilia. Arranged in series by geographical location and format. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, glass plate and nitrate film negatives may be consulted only with permission of the Curator of Documentary Arts.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The William Hillman Shockley photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as purchases from 2010 to 2015.
Biographical Note
William Hillman Shockley (1855-1925) was an American mining engineer and amateur photographer and botanist. He was born in New Bedford, Massachusetts and educated at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Trained as a mining engineer, he first worked in Florida and California, then from late 1896 to 1905 traveled to China, Russia, Korea, and Australia in search of mining opportunities, chiefly in gold, silver, iron ore, coal, copper, and petroleum. While in Nevada and Texas, he also investigated mercury mines. He also traveled extensively to investigate mining interests in Perú, Argentina, Chile, Sudan, Eritrea, and Egypt, and visited many European cities.
Shockley married May Bradford, Missouri-born mining surveyor in Nevada and federal deputy surveyor of the mineral lands, in London in 1908. After residing in London, the Shockleys returned to Nevada in 1913, three years after the birth of their son. After returning to London for many years, they eventually settled in Palo Alto, California. William H. Shockley died in Los Angeles in 1925, and May Bradford Shockley in 1977. Their only child, William B., became known as the inventor of the transistor and won the Nobel Prize for Physics in 1956.
Collection Overview
Collection contains over 2200 black-and-white images taken by W.H. Shockley during his world travels as a mining engineer. Locations include China (including Manchuria), Korea, India, Japan, Australia, and Russia (including Siberia), between the years of 1897 and 1909. Subjects featured include local citizens and officials, and soldiers; Europeans (including businessmen, miners, diplomats, tourists, missionaries); indigenous peoples and their communities; mining operations (iron ore, gold, petroleum, and coal); ancient walls and forts; religious structures and art; street scenes; remote hamlets and camps; fields, rivers, mountains, geological formations, and other landscapes; domestic animals; and caravans and other forms of transportation, including railroads. There are many other work scenes in addition to mining settings. Other formats in the collection include negatives, modern photographic prints, correspondence, and a few artifacts and memorabilia. Shockley also documented his experiences in Russia, China, and other places in articles and presentations for the mining industry; some are available online (retrieved April 2016).
The bulk of the collection is made up of 2,227 vintage black-and-white contact prints measuring from 2 1/2 x 3 1/2 inches to 4x6 inches, many of which bear original captions in Shockley's hand. They are arranged in series by geographical location and date of travel. Accompanying these small prints is a small set of larger card-mounted photographs of Shockley family members, including Shockley's wife, May Bradford Shockley, and their young son William B. Shockley. There are also over 400 original nitrate film and glass plate negatives, some of which contain images not found elsewhere in the collection.
Several hundred modern 8x10 inch prints were made by a photo collector from Shockley's original negatives, chiefly of Russia and Siberia; some of these are unique images not found among the small original prints, including images of an upper-class family on an unidentified estate in England.
Non-photographic materials consist of Shockley's field notebook from India containing an index of photographs he took there; mica mineral samples from India; original envelopes and glass plate boxes; and a bound letterbook containing approximately 100 pieces of business correspondence and a few pieces of personal correspondence, dating from 1905 to 1922.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Related Collections
William Hillman Shockley collection
University of Nevada, Las Vegas, Department of Special Collections
William Hillman Shockley Travel Diaries, 1908-1909 [documenting train trips from N.Y. to California]
Beinecke Library, Yale University
William Hillman Shockley Photographs of Peru, 1903 May-October
Beinecke Library, Yale University
William Hillman Shockley Photographs of Sudan, 1905 Janurary-April
Beinecke Library, Yale University
William Hillman Shockley papers
Stanford University Department of Special Collections and University Archives
William [B.] Shockley papers
Stanford University Department of Special Collections and University Archives.
The papers of William B. Shockley contain many materials relating to his parents, W. H. Shockley and May Bradford Shockley
Sidney D. Gamble photographs of China
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Americans in the land of Lenin: documentary photographs of Early Soviet Russia (digital collection from Frank Whitson Fetter and Robert Eichelberger papers)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: China (further divided into Beijing, Hebei, Henan, Hunan, Jinjanggouliang, Manchuria, Shanghai, Shanxi, Other Locations, and Unidentified Locations); India; Japan; Korea; Australia; Russia (subdivided into Siberia, Bogoslovsk and Klyuchi); and smaller series, Other Places and Other Subjects. Photographs are followed by a Negatives and Papers series.
Australia -- History; Australia -- Pictorial works; Beijing (China) -- Pictorial works; China -- Economic conditions -- 1644-1912; China -- History -- 1861-1912; China -- Pictorial works; Coal mines and mining -- Pictorial works; Documentary Photography -- Australia; Documentary Photography -- China; Documentary Photography -- India; Documentary Photography -- Japan; Documentary Photography -- Korea; Documentary Photography -- Russia; Gold mines and mining -- Pictorial works; Great Britain -- Foreign relations -- 19th century; India -- History -- 19th century; India -- Pictorial works; Indigenous peoples -- Pictorial works; Japan -- Pictorial works; Korea -- History -- 1864-1910; Korea -- Pictorial works; Manchuria (China) -- Pictorial works; Mining engineering -- Pictorial works; Russia -- Economic conditions -- 1861-1917; Russia -- History -- 1801-1917; Russia -- Pictorial works; Shanghai (China) -- Pictorial works; Siberia (Russia) -- History -- 19th century; Siberia (Russia) -- Pictorial works; United States -- Foreign relations; Black-and-white photographs; Cellulose nitrate film; Gelatin silver prints; Glass plate negatives; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University); Shockley, W. H., 1855-1925
- China: Beijing, 1897-1898; 179 prints
  Scope and Contents
  Images in this large series consist of Beijing city scenes, chiefly taken on the street, with a handful of photographs taken in rural areas outside the city limits. Photographs in this large series focus on urban subjects, but there are also some images taken outside the city of farms and villages. Work scenes show people operating water mills, refining salt, making cloisonne, smelting iron, washing quartz gold, fishing from boats, and milling wheat. Other scenes feature a funeral procession, an honor guard procession, camel trains, ferry boats, city walls, temples and pagodas, a bell tower, astronomy instruments, a Christian church, private gardens and parks in Peking, the Great Wall, and Buddhist stone carvings.
  People featured include Qing dynasty (Manchu) government officers, Manchu men and women, poor people and beggars, wealthy Chinese families, laborers, women in doorways (some possibly prostitutes), fortune tellers, and street sellers of incense and herbs. Shockley's captions frequently mention social class and conditions, for example noting which women had bound feet. Portraits of family groups often include their most prized material possessions. There are images of Western businessmen and women, including travelers in Shockley's party, and buildings associated with the British legation and European businesses, as well as Chinese government buildings.
  There are a few portraits of William Pritchard Morgan, a lawyer, politician, and investor in mining concerns, and his family, with whom Shockley seems to have spent considerable time visiting and touring; more are found in the Shanghai series.
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0001)
    Description
    Westerner in front of six Chinese standing on steps
    Description (Chinese)
    六个中国人站在台阶上，一个外国人站在他们前面
    Original ID
    403
  - Exterior Imperial city Peking, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0002)
    Title (Chinese)
    紫禁城外景 [中华门，北京
    411
  - Peking / near British legation, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0003)
    英国公使馆附近 / 北京
    413
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0004)
    Cart mired in mud on a road
    车陷入泥泞的道路上
    414
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0005)
    People operating a water well
    井中汲水
    416
  - Pai Lou Peking, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0006)
    牌楼，北京
    Arched gate
    拱门
    417
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0007)
    Street and house
    街道和房子
    418
  - Manchu women Peking, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0008)
    满族妇女，北京
    419
  - Peking from wall, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0009)
    从城墙观北京城
    420
  - Poor Chinese outside wall, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0010)
    紧靠城墙外的穷苦人棚屋
    422
  - Christian, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0011)
    教徒
    Large church, frontal view from distance
    大教堂，正门远望
    423
  - Nice house for westerners in Peking, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0012)
    外国人在北京居住的好房子
    Western man and woman with Chinese person (servant?)
    外国男女和中国（仆人？)
    424
  - Astronomical Instruments near Peking, 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0013)
    各种天文观测仪，北京附近
    425
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0014)
    Boy practicing archery
    男孩练习射箭
    427
  - Peking, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0015)
    北京
    Chinese gathering, one Westerner
    聚集的一些人，一个外国人
    428
  - Astronomical Instruments; observatory on the wall, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0016)
    （观象台）上的天文观测仪器
    429
  - Used to stand on the Tartar wall of Peking, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0017)
    曾经放在内城墙（天文台）的
    Shockley posing with astronomy instrument
    天文观测仪
    430
  - Peking, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0018)
    Astronomy instrument
    431
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0019)
    432
  - Xtra one or taken from wall, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0020)
    从（天文台）搬下来的另一个
    433
  - Stalls. For Civil Service Examinations in Peking, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0021)
    北京科举考试考场上的单间小房
    435
  - Confucius Temple Peking, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0022)
    孔庙，北京
    437
  - Manchu women / Large feet, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0023)
    几位满族妇女，大脚
    440
  - Oldest buildings in Peking / from Mongol times/ Drum Tower / Not the Bell Tower, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0024)
    北京最古老的建筑/建于蒙古时期//鼓楼 / 不是钟楼
    441
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0025)
    Drum tower
    鼓楼
    442
  - Funeral / image of favorite animal (horse) to be burned, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0026)
    葬礼上常见的纸糊动物（马），用来焚烧
    443
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0027)
    Funeral
    葬礼
    445
  - Confucius Temple, Peking, 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0028)
    446
  - Manchu, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0029)
    满族
    Woman holding up baby
    妇女抱着一个外国小孩
    449
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0030)
    Chinese man with a Western child on donkey
    中国男人牵着一匹驴，马上坐着一名外国小孩
    453
  - Dressed for begging / sells incense, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0031)
    卖香的乞丐男孩
    Youth in tattered clothing
    青年衣衫褴褛
    461
  - Dromedary came a long way, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0032)
    路边长长的驼队
    476
  - Chien Men, Peking, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0033)
    前门, 北京
    495
  - Beggars, Peking, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0034)
    乞丐，北京
    482
  - Firing Cloisonne's [sic], circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0035)
    烧制景泰蓝
    483
  - Smelt iron small [?], circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0036)
    小熔炉 [?]
    Western man observing Chinese men
    西方人观察中国男人
    484
  - Curio Dealer, Peking, 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0037)
    古玩商，北京
    494
  - Gate man at Peking hotel driving away man stealing [fragments?] of wood, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0038)
    北京酒店门房赶走捡拾 [碎 ?] 木头的男子
  - Beggar, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0039)
    乞丐
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0040)
    Beggars gathered outside building
    门外聚集的几个乞丐
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0041)
    Beggars sleeping in alley
    乞丐睡在巷子里
  - Edmunds. Power. Stubbs. / First Chinese inn, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0042)
    埃德蒙兹、鲍尔、斯塔布斯/第一家来中国旅店
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0043)
    Western man, two Chinese men carrying processional banners
    一名外国男子，两名中国男子扛着回避牌子
  - Typical façade rich home, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0044)
    典型富裕人家的房屋正面
  - Small town [tour?] city gate, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0045)
    宅院大门外的人群
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0046)
    Western girl sitting in front of sundial
    外国小女孩坐在日晷前
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0047)
    Western girl sitting in front of stone lion
    Relation
    version of RL01177-P-0046
  - Bourgeois gentility taking your bird for a walk for air / Western child, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0048)
    富裕的中国人温文尔雅的出来遛鸟/外国小孩
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0049)
    Western woman with baby
    抱着婴儿的外国妇女
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0050)
    Three Western men looking at something off camera
    三个外国男人注视镜头外的某处
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0051)
    Western man and Chinese man posing on steps
    一名外国人和一名中国人站在台阶上照相
  - Wealthy Chinese / 2 wives, water pipe / showing off making a statement, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0052)
    中国富人和他的两名妻子，桌上的水烟袋/展示他的富裕生活
    Curio dealer
    古玩商
  - Bound feet on right, circa 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0053)
    站在右边是裹小脚的
    Curio dealer posing with family group, William Pritchard Morgan, and baby
    古玩商、他的家人与手抱婴儿的外国男子一起拍照
    Note
    William Pritchard Morgan was a Welch-born lawyer, politician, and investor in mining concerns in Wales, China and Australia.
  - Manchu, circa 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0054)
    满族男人
    Curio dealer posing by a small table
    古玩商站在小桌边
  - Chinese [in the?] Manchu regime / Best possession, circa 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0055)
    清朝汉人/最值钱的财富
  - Curio Dealer Peking, 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0056)
    Similar to image P-494.
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0057)
    Curio dealer's family
    古玩商一家的合影
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0058)
    Portrait of male child (curio dealer's son?), seated with a small book
    古玩商的儿子坐在桌边的椅子上，手拿一本小书
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0059)
    Wealthy Chinese man
    中国富人
  - Manchu / Manchu cap with [better?] button, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0060)
    满族 / 头戴瓜皮帽的满族男子[更好的帽饰 ?]
  - Important Chinese, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0061)
    一位中国显要
    Group of men posing in a courtyard
    和仆从在院子里合影
  - Peking Curio dealer, circa 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0062)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0063)
    Man with umbrella
    打伞的男子
  - Rich Chinese lady and Possession, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0064)
    有钱的中国妇女和她的财产
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0065)
    Chinese man by window
    窗边的中国男人
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0066)
    Chinese man by doorway
    门边的中国男人
    version of RL01177-P-0065
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0067)
    Man with naked children
    中国男人带着裸体的孩子们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0068)
    version of RL01177-P-0067
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0069)
    Group of workers
    一群工人在休息
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0070)
    Child posing near a well?
    井边上的男孩
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0071)
    Group of people working at the bottom of a hill
    山脚处正在劳作的人们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0072)
    Group of workers in quarry looking up at camera
    劳作的人们望向镜头
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0073)
    Man in white with large hat posing on a hillside
    白衣男子带着宽沿大帽子站在山坡上
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0074)
    Man with baby
    抱着小孩的男子
  - Hired boys procession, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0075)
    受雇佣参加出行仪仗的男孩们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0076)
    Two workers eating at an outdoor table
    桌边吃饭的两个男子
  - Li Hung Chang's Temple, Peking, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0077)
    李鸿章的家庙，北京
  - Peking city wall, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0078)
    北京城墙
  - Adobe bricks, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0079)
    City gate and tower
    土砖 城门楼
  - Peking wall we believe, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0080)
    我们认为是北京城墙
  - Façade wall / Peking Gate / just outside, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0081)
    北京城
  - Peking Wall, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0082)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0083)
    Entrance to Chinese Prime Minister of Foreign Affairs building
    总理外国事务衙门门
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0084)
    Trees in a courtyard
    庭院中的三棵树
  - Top Wall Peking, 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0085)
    北京城墙上
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0086)
    Pai lou (arched gateway)
    牌楼
  - Misses Pritchard-Morgan Peking, 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0087)
    两位普里查德·摩根小姐 / 北京
  - Private grounds. Chinese Mandarin / Peking, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0088)
    官员的私家庭院 / 北京
  - Peking City Wall ?, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0089)
    北京城墙 ?
  - Grounds of Chinese Mandarin / Peking, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0090)
    中国满洲人的庭院/北京
  - Pagoda, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0091)
    塔
  - Pagoda near Liu-Li-Hei, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0092)
    琉璃河附近的佛塔
    Includes railroad
    铁轨
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0093)
    Distant view of 13-story pagoda near Liu-Li-Hei, taken from field
    田野远处的塔
    version of RL01177-P-0092
  - Important temple, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0094)
    重要的寺院
  - Typical upper middle class home / old folks at back younger at sides, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0095)
    典型的上层中产阶级家庭/老人住在后面，年轻人住在两边
  - Peking club from wall, 1898 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0096)
    从城墙上看北京俱乐部
  - Dagoba - (Tibetan Pagoda) in Pei Hai, park in Peking, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0097)
    舍利塔 - （藏式佛塔） 在北海公园，北京
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0098)
    Buddhist sculpture relief
    浮雕石佛像
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0099)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0100)
    Carpenter working in the courtyard
    木匠在院子里工作
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0101)
    Man sitting on a bench in a gateway
    坐在门口长椅上的人
  - Maps / Enameled bucket / Church, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0102)
    挂着的地图/搪瓷桶/教会
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0103)
    Tall vase
    一个高大的花瓶
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0104)
    version of RL01177-P-0103
  - Scene of a procession in Peking, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0105)
    北京出行仪仗的场景
    Funeral procession
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0106)
    Funeral procession; decorated horses and riders passing through an unpaved street
    盛装的骑马者通过一条土路
  - Templeware for sale outside temple, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0107)
    供瓶在寺庙外售
  - Begging priest, Peking, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0108)
    化缘的僧人，北京
    In front of a clothing store
    在一家估衣店前
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0109)
    Three men in front of an antiques store
    三名男子站在茹古斋前
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0110)
    People walking on a market street
    行走在商街上的人们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0111.1)
    Funeral procession on a market street in Peking
    北京的商业街上的葬礼队伍
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0111.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0111
  - Near Li Hung Chang Yamen / Peking, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0112)
    李鸿章的总理衙门附近 / 北京
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0113)
    Woman and many children near an open door
    一个妇女和几个孩子站在敞开的门口往里看
  - Pumpkin, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0114)
    南瓜
    Cart full of pumpkins
    车满pumkins的
  - Peking, 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0115)
    Market street scene
    一条商业街
  - Pa/kwa / Fortune Teller / Eight trigrams, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0116)
    八卦 / 算命先生
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0117)
    Men sitting on and among large bundles
    男人们坐在大捆货物中间
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0118)
    Group of people
    人群
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0119)
    Procession of honor guard carrying ceremonial umbrellas
    出行仪仗
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 1, Print RL01177-P-0120)
    Shockley posing next to honor guard procession
    外国男子与仪仗人员合影